LUCAS PEREIRA MOTIZUKI

E: motizukilucas@gmail.com • T: +55 (21) 98349-4540 • Rio de Janeiro, RJ - 28915-530 • L: linkedin.com/in/motizukilucas • G: https://github.com/motizukilucas • W: https://motizuki.me/

Profile

Computer Science graduate from Veiga de Almeida University. 5 years of professional experience with technology including research, development and devops experiences. **Fluent in English.** Skills:

Web Frameworks (Laravel & Rails) • Automated testing (PHPUnit & RSpec) • JQuery (JavaScript) • Database engines (MySQL & PSQL) • Git • Docker • Scrum • Amazon AWS (CloudFormation, EC2, RDS, CloudWatch, Route53, S3, CodePipeline, ELB, ECS, ECR, CodeBuild, SystemManager, SystemManager, VPC, IAM, Lightsail, Amplify, EKS & Lambda) • Wordpress • Nginx & Apache • Responsive Design (Bootstrap) • Office Apps

Professional Experience

DevOps • Ezops.Cloud • Rio de Janeiro, RJ • Feb, 2021 - present

Automating projects based on DevOps techniques with AWS infrastructure. Responsible for task managing, requirements engineering and client satisfaction.

My work involves the constant use of English as we have clients from all over the world. But I am currently in contact with mainly clients and their developers from the States, Europe and India. One of my job's responsibilities is actively participating and running online meetings with the clients. So as a parallel of this, I end up also being responsible for client satisfaction and a bit of managing the task priority.

The main branch of my job is doing actual devops development. We mainly work with AWS and web applications, so I'm very comfortable with deploying CI/CD applications for the web. Using RDS, ECS with EC2, codepipeline and codebuild, with of course the routing behind it like DNS in Route53, pointing to load balancers and distributing the load for the instances. And also the instances have auto scaling enabled.

There are also other scenarios that don't fall under this standard solution, for example I've recently developed a **lambda** function in **python** to trigger whenever someone pushes a CSV file to a **S3** bucket, it will process that data and push it to a **RDS**.

Recently I've been also working with **Azure, GCP & OCI.** I've developed a pipeline that will build images from an Azure's repository, and push them to a GCP registry then deploy it to a kubernetes cluster. For my benefit there was a very straightforward tutorial from google taching most of the steps required.

On OCI I've been working with **terraform** to build a full environment, from buckets, policies and what not, to deploy a kubernetes based application.

Full-stack Developer • Bilo • Rio de Janeiro, RJ • Aug, 2018 - Feb, 2020

Developed applications for both front and back end. Developed payment processing and registration services along with a notification system. Created a range of automated functional tests, aiming to guarantee the quality of several systems, which affected more than 141 thousand users.

In this experience I was presented with several technologies that I wasn't using actively like **Git**, **Docker**, **docker-compose**, **Laravel**, **unit testing** (in the form of **PHPUnit** and **RSpec**) also with **Rails**.

This was a startup company in which the main goal was the development of an event hub, where customers would be able to not only get their tickets, but also during the event buy drinks on their phones, get a QR code and retrieve it in the bars. So it was like a software to centralize the customer's experience.

We had this legacy code, which was written in **rails** that had a portal for administration, and a front-end page for actually selling the tickets. But it wasn't very fast, so our idea was to modernize it in **Laravel** and add the experience during the event. At one point under development I was also tasked with the development of unit and function tests, starting for the legacy code with **rspec**, then later moving into **phpunit**.

Research & Development Intern • ILUMNO • Rio de Janeiro, RJ • Aug, 2017 - Jul, 2018

The main scope here was the development of a dynamic questionnaire that would adjust to the student's learning style, for example if the student were more on the visual side, the system would favor questions with more images. The questionnaire was a web page presented in an iframe, mainly using **php** together with a **mysql** database. After the development and testing phase of the application, the work revolved into treating data, like in case of duplication. Also creating more specialized queries to retrieve it. This was a questionnaire that was a main part of a discipline evaluation system.

Education

One of the highlights of my formation was being a **tutor** for **algorithms & programming** class. Where I assisted the teacher and the students, created several support materials and kept the lab in order.

My final thesis was in independent game development, even though the idea of independence is related with the financial status of a product, developers are pushing the limits to represent an independent ethos. The choice of a game engine for an independent developer is mostly a personal choice, engines out there are more than suited to fit their purpose. The need for documenting a production has proved itself, developers can benefit a lot by using documents such as SGDDs (short game design document) for guiding the development process. If used together with prototyping, create a powerful combo to start off the game. With both SGDD and prototyping discussed in this document, I was able to develop a prototype of a platformer game, exploring the capabilities of the chosen game engine, developing with success collision, movement and object instancing mechanics. Although most of the results achieved can be considered satisfactory, there's a clear gap between the current prototype and it's final desired state.